Guide to the First Presbyterian Church of Ithaca records,1801-2010.
First Presbyterian Church of Ithaca records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
First Presbyterian Church of Ithaca records, 1801-2010.
4045
First Presbyterian Church (Ithaca, N.Y.).
44.9 cubic ft.
Publications, Reports, Movie Film
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Subjects include annual reports; births; baptisms; marriages; deaths; buildings and grounds; church finances, governance, history, library, manuals, membership, organizations, and publications; missionary work; pastors; special events; Sunday school; youth programs; Bibles; prayerbooks; music and hymnals; blueprints and maps; and other records of the First Presbyterian Church of Ithaca, Tompkins County, New York.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The First Presbyterian Church of Ithaca was organized January 24, 1804 by Rev. Jedediah Chapman.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Subjects include annual reports; births; baptisms; marriages; deaths; buildings and grounds; church finances, governance, history, library, manuals, membership, organizations, and publications; missionary work; pastors; special events; Sunday school; youth programs; Bibles; prayerbooks; music and hymnals; blueprints and maps; and other records of the First Presbyterian Church of Ithaca, Tompkins County, New York.
Also included is a 5 DVD set of Called to be the First by Elizabeth McKeen and "100 Years of Reflections, 1904-2004," 2009; and a phonograph record of a concert at the church, "The Seven Last Words of Christ," recorded by the Cornell Recording Service of the Cornell Radio Guild, Inc., ca. 1951.
Photographs and files relating to the Kay-Billie-Klaer (KBK) Academy in Ghana, originally sponsored and supported by members of the First Presbyterian Church and named for Kay Ensworth, Billie Philbrick, and Betty Klaer and created by Akrofi and Awo Dzrietror, a couple from Ghana (Akrofi received a M.S. and Ph.D. in Agronomy at Cornell and Awo studied child development at TC3).
SUBJECTS
Names:
First Presbyterian Church (Ithaca, N.Y.).; Chapman, Jedediah.; Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.)
Subjects:
Religion--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Religious institutions--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Education--Ghana
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.).; Tompkins County (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Blueprints.; Maps.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted in part.
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to the OLD printed finding aid. Seachable PDF.
  Not all the material in the collection is covered by the printed finding aid and the printed finding aid above, the guide below is more current.
- Initial collection through March 2006
  - Annual reports; births; baptisms; marriages; deaths; buildings and grounds, 1858-1979 (Box 1)
  - Buildings and grounds; list of blueprints and maps; Church and community; Church finances RESTRICTED, 1816-1978 (Box 2)
  - Church finances RESTRICTED, 1929-1955 (Box 3)
  - Church finances RESTRICTED, ca.1890’s-1979 (Box 4)
  - Church finances RESTRICTED, 1826-1965 (Box 5)
  - Church finances RESTRICTED, 1950-1959 (Box 6)
  - Church finances RESTRICTED, 1916-1977 (Box 7)
  - Church governance, 1927-1977 (Box 8)
  - Church governance, 1963-1975 (Box 9)
  - Church governance; Church history; Church library; Church manuals and membership, 1858-1978 (Box 10)
  - Church manuals and membership; Church organizations, 1832-1977 (Box 11)
  - Church organizations, 1887-1966 (Box 12)
  - Church publications, 1879-1978 (Box 13)
  - Church publications; employment; educational programs, Groton community parish; miscellaneous, 1861-1980 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous; miscellaneous books, music and hymnals; missionary literature; missionary work; pastors, 1801-1974 (Box 15)
  - First Presbyterian Church in Cayuta (Newfield) records, 2 vols., 1817-1879 (Box 15)
  - Missionary work; newspaper clippings, 1881-1976 (Box 16)
  - Newspaper clippings; pastors; planning; presbytery; synod; United Presbyterian Church of America; religious publications and periodicals; special events; social events RESTRICTED, 1815-1979 (Box 17)
  - Sunday school; youth programs, 1880’s-1977 (Box 18)
  - Bibles, prayer books, etc., 1866-1940 (Box 19)
  - Births; baptisms; marriages; deaths; Bibles, prayer books, etc.; Church attendance; Church finances RESTRICTED, 1765-1980 (Box 20)
  - Church finances RESTRICTED, 1914-1929, 1960-1964 (Box 21)
  - Church governance, 1816-1896 (Box 21)
  - Church governance, 1916-1960 (Box 22)
  - Church finances RESTRICTED, 1941-1967 (Box 23)
  - Church finances; Church organizations RESTRICTED, 1906-1971 (Box 24)
  - Church finances; Church organizations RESTRICTED, 1949-1969 (Box 25)
  - Church finances RESTRICTED, 1824-1910 (Box 26)
  - Church governance; Church history; Church manuals and membership; Church organizations, 1804-1966 (Box 27)
  - Church manuals and memberships, 1923-1959 (Box 28)
  - Church property; miscellaneous books; missionary literature; missionary work, 1678-1966 (Box 29)
  - Music and hymnals, 1838-1903 (Box 30)
  - Pastors; Presbyterian Church, Ithaca: authors; presbytery; synod; United Presbyterian Church of America; Sunday school, 1781-1927 (Box 31)
  - Church history; Sunday school, 1904-1918 (Box 32)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1900-1918 (Box 33)
  - Buildings and grounds, 1966-1968 (Box 34)
  - Church finances; Church governance; miscellaneous; missionary work; pastors, 1781-1961 (Box 35)
  - Church Finances; Church Organizations; Newspaper Clippings; Pastors; Religious Publications and Periodicals RESTRICTED, 1815-1941 (Box 36)
  - Bibles, Prayer Books, etc., 1880’s (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous; photographs, 1910-1919 (Box 38)
  - Photographs (Box 39)
  - Watercolors (Box 40)
  - Church Finances RESTRICTED, 1974 (Box 41-42)
  - Miscellaneous, 1900-1901 (Box 43)
  - Pictorial directory of parishioners (commemorates 175 years), 1979 (Box 43)
  - Historical items, Church Finances, 1807-1975 (Box 44)
  - Church Finances, 1931-1950 (Box 45)
  - Church Finances, 1950-1965 (Box 46)
  - Bulletins (bound in 7 vols.), 2001-2008 (Box 47)
  - Bulletins (not complete), 1880-1895 (Box 48)
  - Bulletins: incomplete, 1896, 1905, 1978 (Box 48)
  - Bulletins: complete (1908-9.13 - 1910-6.26 [1 vol.], 1910-9.4 - 1912-12.29 [1 vol.] ) (Box 48)
    Includes 1906-1912, 1920-1926, 1976-1977, 1979-1989
  - Bulletins: at Cornell (Box 48)
    Includes 1913-1919, 1927-1964
  - Bulletins: missing at FPCI, 1970-1975 (Box 48)
  - Bulletins: complete (Box 49)
    Includes 1989-1996, 1998-2000
  - Bulletins: incomplete, 1997 (Box 49)
  - Spotlight Addenda: Nos. 2-3, 1961 (Box 50)
  - Spotlight Addenda: Nos. 1-3, 1963 (Box 50)
  - Spotlight Addenda: Nos. 2-3, 1965 (Box 50)
  - Spotlight Addenda: June, Nos. 1-2, 1968 (Box 50)
  - Spotlight Addenda: Nos. 3-4, 1969 (Box 50)
  - Good News: complete (vols. 1-2, 5-9, 11-16, 17 [1993]-21/22) (Box 50)
    Includes 1975-1976, 1979-1984, 1986-1991, 1993-1997
  - Good News: incomplete (vols. 3-4, 10, 17 [1992], 22/23 [1998]-28) (Box 50)
    Includes 1977-1978, 1985, 1992, 1998-2004
- Additional material from March 2006
  - Ithaca, N.Y. First Presbyterian Church, Articles of Faith [formerly Rare/BX/9211/I89/F51], 1830 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Home Missionary Society, 1842 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Home Missionary Society, 1844 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Home Missionary Society, 1845 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Home Missionary Society, 1849 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Home Missionary Society, 5/1841, 5/1844, 5/1849, 1841-1849 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Manual of Rules/Regulations, 1858, 1880, 1858-1880 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Manual of Rules/Regulations, Adopted 1832, 1832 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Manual of Rules/Regulations, Adopted 1942, 1958, 1942-1958 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Membership Roll, 1874, 1889, 1874-1889 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Membership Roll, 1/1882, 1/1883, 1882-1883 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Membership Roll, 1/1889, 1/1887, 4/1885, 1885-1889 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Membership Roll, 1/1891, 1/1893, 1891-1893 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Membership Roll, 2/1896; 4 lists, (19thC), 1896 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Membership Roll, 5/1902, 1902 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Membership Roll, 3/1906, 1/1911, 1906-1911 (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Membership Roll, 9/1915, 6/1916, 1915-1916 (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Membership Roll, 7/1916, 4/1920, 4/1925, 1916-1925 (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - Membership Roll, 1923, 1928; dismissions, 1928, 1923-1928 (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - Membership Roll, 4/1925, 1/1930, 1925-1930 (Box 51, Folder 20)
  - Membership Roll, 1934, 1935, 1937, 1938, 1934-1938 (Box 51, Folder 21)
  - Membership Roll, 5/1924, 2/1930-2/1932, 1924-1932 (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - Membership Roll, 1941 (Box 51, Folder 23)
  - Membership Roll [corrected 1967], 1966, 1967 (Box 51, Folder 24)
  - Membership Roll, 1/1968, 1968 (Box 51, Folder 25)
  - Membership Forms: A-H (Box 51, Folder 26)
  - Membership Forms: I-R (Box 51, Folder 27)
  - Membership Forms: S-Z (Box 51, Folder 28)
  - Dorcas Society, 1902-1903 (Box 51, Folder 29)
  - Woman’s Union, 1903-1904 - 1911-1912, 1903-1912 (Box 51, Folder 29)
  - Woman’s Aid Society (2 c. 1916-1917), 1881-1884 1912-1913 - 1918-1919: letters, 1881-1884, 1912-1919 (Box 51, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous, 1854, 1880, 1902, 1914, 1922, 1934, 1935; record of Sunday School classes 1933-34, 1934-35, 1937-38, 1854-1935 (Box 51, Folder 30)
  - Ladies Prayer Meeting Attendance Records, 1892-1900 (Box 51, Folder 31)
  - West Hill Prayer Meeting, 1900-1914 (Box 51, Folder 31)
  - Ernestine Circle Favorite Recipes, 1907-1967 (Box 51, Folder 32)
  - Ernestine Circle Records Meetings & Activities, 1962-1971 (Box 51, Folder 33)
  - Meetings of the Woman’s Missionary Society, 1900-1901 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Woman’s Missionary Society, 1902-1903 - 1903-1904, 1907-1908 - 1910-1911, 1902-1911 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Monday Evening Missionary Society, Secretary’s Book, Book II, 1932-1943 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Constitution of Monday Evening Missionary Society, 1933 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Woman’s Missionary Society: Officers and Committees, 1934-1935 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Report of Monday Evening Missionary Society, 1942-1943 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Women’s Association, 1948-1949 - 1949-1950, 1960-1961 - 1961-1962, 1968-1969, 1948-1969 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Miss M. Williams, 1911, 1920, 1911-1920 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Letters of the President of the Society, 1881, 1882, 1881-1882 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Misc. notes (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence to & from Mrs. Stryker in Utah re Mormonism, 1881 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Form: Board of Home Missions, Paw Paw Grove, Illinois (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Form: Presbyterian Board of Relief for Disabled Ministers (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Women’s Aid Society documents collected by Miss Augusta Williams, 1881-1882 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Women’s Aid Society "Favorite Recipes" (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Miscellany, 1886, 1887, 1917-1918, 1920, 1934, 1942: resolution on death of Henry Shaler Williams, 1918; David Stewart Curry letter, 1920, 1886-1942 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Constitution of the Sunday School of the First Presbyterian Church of Ithaca, New York (2 c.), 1902 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - "Opening Doors," Volume 13, #’s 2, 3, 1961 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Ithaca Presbyterian Sunday School Survey, ca. 1930 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Religious Education leaflets, 1916, 1977, 1916-1977 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Sunday School: Program, 1917 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Bible Study Courses, 1922-1923 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Sunday School Files: Teachers, Orricers, Members, Junior Department, Intermediate, Senior, 1930-1932 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Sunday School Superintendents and Officers Meeting minutes, 1957-1961 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Church School, 1957-1962 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Rev. W. Wisner, "The Line of Demarcation between the Secular Kingdoms of this World and the Spiritual Kingdom of the Lord Jesus Christ", 1844 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Rev. A. S. Fiske, "Progress of Christianity in the 19th Century," "A Sermon to the Young", 1889 (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - Installation of the Rev. J. Frederick Fitschen, Jr. (program), 1897 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Evening Service (program), 1884 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Services of Consecration, 1901 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Two clippings, 1911 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Installation of the Reverend John MacIntosh (program), 1912 (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Resolution on Rev. MacIntosh moving to different church (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Memorial Service: Rev. John MacIntosh (program), 1927 (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Letters of Dismission and Acceptance; student and temporary membership cards and certificates, 1920-1925, 1916-1928 (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Lists, 1924-1931 (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Church clippings, 5/1937, 1937 (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - John W. Ross, 1919 (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - Pastoral Nominating Committee, 1919 (Box 52, Folder 22)
  - Pastoral Nominating Committee, 1919-1920 (Box 52, Folder 23)
  - Pastoral Nominating Committee, 1936 (Box 52, Folder 24)
  - Pastoral Nominating Committee, 1940 (Box 52, Folder 25)
  - Ordination Service of William Spaulding Eaton, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 26)
  - Installation Service of Rev. Donald A. Acton, 1957 (Box 52, Folder 26)
  - "My Deaconship" form for Clayton E. Weber, 1939 (Box 52, Folder 26)
  - "Worship in the Presence of God," Sermon by H. A. Moran, 1945 (Box 52, Folder 27)
  - Letter from Rev. F. Sperduto, 1957 (Box 52, Folder 27)
  - Documents concerning Rev. P. D. Clark, 1962-1963 (Box 52, Folder 27)
  - Papers related to Rev. D. G. Howland, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 27)
  - Services in Commemoration of the One Hundredth Anniversary of the First Presbyterian Church of Ithaca, New York, 1/21/1904, 1904 (Box 52, Folder 28)
  - "100 Years of Reflections", 2004 (Box 52, Folder 28)
  - Service of Dedication, First Presbyterian Church, 4/13/1911, 1911 (Box 52, Folder 29)
  - "The Welcome," 1/1908, 9/1909, 12/1911, 10/1912, 1/1913, 1908-1913 (Box 52, Folder 30)
  - New Members, Baptisms, Deaths as recorded in Bulletins, 1908-1937 (Box 52, Folder 31)
  - Church papers, 1915-1932 (Box 52, Folder 32)
  - Wednesday School, 1936-1941 (Box 52, Folder 33)
  - Sunday School, 1933-1959 (Box 52, Folder 33)
  - Educational Committee (Box 52, Folder 33)
  - Membership and Fellowship, 1942-1961 (Box 52, Folder 33)
  - Groton Community Parish, 1935-1939 (Box 52, Folder 33)
  - Book XIV: Membership, 1930-1940 (Box 52, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Committees, 1935-1962 (Box 52, Folder 34)
  - Executive Committee, 1931-1939 (Box 52, Folder 35)
  - Recruiting Committee, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 35)
  - Missionary Society Minutes, 1920-1939 (Box 52, Folder 36)
  - Presbyterian Brotherhood, 1911-1924 (Box 52, Folder 37)
  - Attendance, 1916-1924 (Box 52, Folder 37)
  - Board of Deaconesses, Minutes, 1937-1949 (Box 52, Folder 38)
  - Community Training School of Religious Education, Season 1924, 1924 (Box 52, Folder 39)
  - Applications, Registrations, Students for Week Day School of Religious Education, 1924 (Box 52, Folder 40)
  - Candidates for Regents Credit, 1924 (Box 52, Folder 41)
  - Questions: Old Testament Narrative, text book: Burgess, "Life of Christ", 1923 (Box 52, Folder 42)
  - Questions: "Great Men of the Christian Centuries", 1924 (Box 52, Folder 43)
  - Questions: "Organization and Administration of the Church School", 1924 (Box 52, Folder 44)
  - Students’ Essays to the Questions, 1924 (Box 52, Folder 45)
  - Letter from Superintendent Ithaca Public Schools to Rev. Beattie re submitting All Examination Questions to State Education Dept., 3/31/1924, 1924 (Box 52, Folder 46)
  - Application letters from teachers, 1924 (Box 52, Folder 47)
  - Enrollment figures [card file], 1922-1928 (Box 53)
  - Woman’s Foreign Missionary Meetings: Hostesses, 1905 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Woman’s Foreign Missionary Meetings: Hosts, 1905 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1862-1863, 1864-1866, 1862-1866 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1864, 1868, 1869-1870, 1871, 1873-1875, 1878, 1880, 1885-1886, 1864-1886 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1866-1867, 1868-1869, 1866-1869 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1871-1872, 1873, 1871-1873 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1874-1875, 1875-1876, 1874-1876 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1876-1877, 1877-1878, 1876-1878 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1878, 1879-1880, 1878-1880 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1881-1882, 1884, 1881-1884 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1887-1888, 1889-1890, 1887-1890 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1891, 1891-1892, 1892, 1891-1892 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1895, 1897, 1895-1897 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1898, 1899, 1898-1899 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1900, 1901, 1900-1901 (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1902, 1903, 1904, 1902-1904 (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Sunday School Attendance Records, 1905, 1905 (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Primary Stories, Course I: Nos. 6, 12, 15, 22, 25, 29, 30-31, 33-37, 40-42, 44-45, 50-51, 1928 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Primary Stories, Course II: Nos. 1-4, 7-9, 12, 14, 17, 19, 21, 23, 25, 27, 37-39, 41-45, 52, 1928 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Primary Stories, Course III: Nos. 3, 5-6, 8, 10, 11, 13, 15, 17, 20, 21, 23-24, 1928 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Beginners’ Stories, Part I, Nos. 3, 5, 7-11, 13, 1928 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Beginners’ Stories, Part 2, Nos. 16, 18-21, 24, 25, 1928 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Beginners’ Stories, Part 4, Nos. 48-49, 51, 1929 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Beginners’ Stories, Part 5, Nos. 54-59, 65, 1929 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Beginners’ Stories, Part 6, Nos. 67-68, 70-72, 1929 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Beginners’ Stories, Part 7, Nos. 81-82, 84-90, 1930 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Beginners’ Stories, Part 8, Nos.92-93, 96, 98, 102-104, 1930 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Rev. M. Hardin autograph sermons
    - "God’s providence over the essential," 1908, 1908 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - "Laborers together with God," 1912, 1912 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - "Negro Problem Cleric Act," 1914, 1914 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - "All bell???ners and worth," 1/15/1915, 1915 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Easter, 4/1915, 1915 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - "God is Love," 9/24/1915, 1915 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - "Christian Missions and World Hope," 2/19/1922, 1922 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Easter, 4/1/1923, 1923 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - "Modern American Church," 11/24/1924, 1924 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - "Our need of worship," 9/25/1925, 1925 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "The Efficient (?) Church," /31/1926, 1926 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "Transformation by the renewal of the Mind," 1/8/1928, 1928 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "The ???? Contribution to the good life," 10/20/1929, 1929 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "Racial Good Will," (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "For the Love of Christ ...," (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "In the sermons which I have been preaching in recent weeks...," (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "Why my bit of labor that has been done on ...," (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "We are confronted here by a problem which ...," (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "It would be the sherest [sic] presumption on my part if ...," (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "Reckon ye also yourselves to be dead indeed unto sin but alive with God through Jesus Christ ...," (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "Happy is he that condemneth not himself in that thing which he alloweth," (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - "How can I do this great wickedness, and sin against God," (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - "The Church and the Child," (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - "Your foreign missionary committee would respectly [sic] report ....," (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - "Jesus came into Galilee preaching the Gospel of God (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - "Let your loins be girded about and your lamps burning ...," (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - "Christianity and the city," (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - "What is more?," (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - "God’s resources and Man’s Need," (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - "Great is our God," (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Rev. M. Hardin printed and typescript sermons
    - "Cast thy bread upon the waters...," 2/11/1912 [t.s.], 1912 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "Civilization at the Cross-Roads," 1916, 1916 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "My Christmas Confession of Faith," 12/25/1920, 1920 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Religion in the Life of Abraham Lincoln," 2/13/1921, 1921 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "Mr. Bryan, Evolution, and religion, 3/12/1922, 1922 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "Shall there be Intellectual Freedom in the Presbyterian Church?," 11/5/1922, 1922 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "The True Religion," 1/14/1923, 1923 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "The Church and The University," 2/18/1923, 1923 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "The General Assembly, Mr. Bryan and Dr. Fosdick, 5/27/1923, 1923 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "Christianity and War," 1/13/1924, 1924 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "What Are the Modernists Trying to Do?," 1/20/1924, 1924 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "The Presbyterian Church and Intellectual Freedom," 5/10/1925, 1925 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "Faith Tested by Experience," 4/11/1926, 1926 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "Communism’s Challenge to Christianity, 4/18/1926, 1926 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "In My Father’s House," 7/1926 (published in "The Church Tower), 1926 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "Pioneering with Christ," 3/8/1931, 1931 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "The President of the United States on Lawlessness," [t.s.] (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Three bulletins (programs) from services, 3/22/1931, 2/18/1934, 9/23/1934, 1931-1934 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Roll and directory (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - BOXES 56-63 ARE RESTRICTED
  - Receipt books, 1925-1926, 1943 RESTRICTED, 1925-1943 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Quarterly Statements and Receipts RESTRICTED, 1927-1929 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Quarterly Statements and Receipts RESTRICTED, 1928-1929 (Box 56, Folder 5-Mar)
  - Receipted Bills for Chapel Repairs RESTRICTED, 1876 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1864-1866 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1867 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1868 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1869 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1870 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1871 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1872 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1873 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1874 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1875 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1876 (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1877 (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1878 (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1879 (Box 56, Folder 20)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1880 (Box 56, Folder 21)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1881 (Box 56, Folder 22)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1882 (Box 56, Folder 23)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1883 (Box 56, Folder 24)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1884 (Box 56, Folder 25)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1885 (Box 56, Folder 26)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1886 (Box 56, Folder 27)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1886 (Box 56, Folder 28)
  - Report to Cayuga Presbytery, 4/1/1886 RESTRICTED, 1886 (Box 56, Folder 28)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 29)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1888 (Box 56, Folder 30)
  - Receipts, Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence explaining outstanding debt RESTRICTED, 1890 (Box 56, Folder 32)
  - Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1889-1891 (Box 56, Folder 33)
  - Vouchers RESTRICTED, 1892-1894 (Box 56, Folder 34)
  - Certificates RESTRICTED, 1854-1859 (Box 56, Folder 35)